Dragos Străinu

- str.dr4605@gmail.com
- +40 745 395 505 / +373 69 292 120
- github.com/strdr4605
- stackoverflow.com/users/5458200/
- linkedin.com/in/dragos-strainu

I am passionate about IT. I am a team player and always aim for teamwork, code review, documentation, discussion whether it is a complex project or a project just for fun. My hobbies are Hackathons and IT events, where I exchange my experience with people and learn new professional and personal skills. I also like mentoring and helping people in software engineering. I share my experience on strdr4605.github.io.

Education

- 01.09.2019-PRESENT Master's Degree in Computer Science, Technical University of Moldova
- 01.10.2017-18.07.2018 University of Siegen, Germany, Computer Science (Erasmus exchange)
- 01.09.2015-28.05.2019 Bachelor's Diploma in Computer Science (Licentiate Engineer), Technical University of Moldova
- 01.09.2012-16.06.2016 Diploma of Professional Studies (Technician), Financial Banking College, Speciality Informatics

Experience

- 02.11.2020-PRESENT Amazon | Front End Engineer (Customer Cloud Security)
 To be completed...
- 20.12.2018–04.09.2020 **GoParrot.ai** | Online Ordering Platform on Microservices Architecture I was responsible for a white-label mobile product with 7+ apps.
 - I wrote automation scripts, design proposals, project documentation and configured development flow.
 - My team and I worked on a new version of the Platform using *React Nativel ReactJS* with 40%+ code shared between mobile and web.

I worked on a service that synchronize database with partners APIs and reduced manual work from 1 week to 15 minutes.

A big part of my professional experience comes from **36 Hackathons** where I developed front-end/back-end/mobile apps and games. Also, I contribute to **30+ open-source projects**.

- mockingcase: I created and maintain a *Node.js* package that converts a string to mockingCaSe. Friendly documentation, unit tests, jsdoc and types for *TypeScript*. I write feature requirements and documentation, review pull requests, and guide 15+ first-time contributors on open-source.
- jump2header: I created a tool that adds markdown links to improve navigation in long README.md files on Github. Used in several popular open-source projects like exceljs and others.
- **redux-requests**: Redux addon to simplify handling of AJAX requests. I added the promise driver, setup the documentation site with docusaurus, and participated in discussions about library design.
- rebble.io: I created a pull request on Github repo and using JavaScript and CSS, I converted SVG static watch logo into Easter egg real-time clock. The hardest part was understanding how SVG works.
- **spacebook**: At NASA Hackathon 2019 my team and I created a *Progressive Web App* which shows Astronomy Picture of the Day in an infinite scroll feed. A (not perfect) app that works by these days.

Skills

Spoken Languages	Languages	Libraries/Platforms/Frameworks
Romanian - Native	JavaScript/TypeScript - Proficient	ReactJS - Proficient
English - Fluent	Version control/GIT - Proficient	React Native - Working knowledge
Russian - Fluent	HTML/CSS - Working knowledge	NodeJS - Working knowledge
German - Beginner	Bash - Working knowledge	VueJS - Basic knowledge
	ReasonML/Ocaml - Basic knowledge	